SMITH KAMLESH GAJJAR

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

smith.gajjar@gmail.com

+91 9820554494

https://smithgajjar.dev

Thane, MH.

SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks

JavaScript, GraphQL, Angular, React, Express.js, Node.js, HTML, CSS/Sass, Kubernetes, TypeScript, MongoDB, Deno, React Native, Redis, SQL, PostgreSQL, Nx

Tools & Platforms

Git, AWS, Webpack, Heroku, Vercel, Docker, Jest, Asana, Jira, Trello, MongoDB Atlas

Design

Figma, Adobe XD, InVision

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2018 - 2021

Vivekanand Educational Society's Institute of Technology

DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2015 - 2018

K.J.Somaiya Polytechnic

SOCIAL



@smith.gajjar09

@smithq09

<u>blogs.smithgajjar.dev</u>

ABOUT

Full Stack Developer and Solutions Architect with a penchant for minimalistic design. I have hands-on experience in developing web applications using several javascript frameworks, managing & optimizing backend infrastructure including deployment, scalability, performance and efficiency.

EXPERIENCE

@TEKIE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

June 2021- Present // Remote

FRONTEND DEVELOPER INTERN

Feb 2021- June 2021 // Remote

- ▶ Building user facing modules for MVP product and a Progressive Web App based on Reactjs.
- ⊳ Building API's and optimizing backend infrastructure to improve scalability and performace based on Nodejs and GraphQL.
- ▶ Managing and optimizing infrastructure based on Kubernetes, Redis, MongoDB and AWS Services such as EC2, EKS, ECR, S3 and CloudFront.
- ▶ Built supporting NPM libraries for MVP product, <u>mongodb-aggregation-builder</u>, <u>tekie-content-editor</u>, <u>tekie-blockly</u>

FRONTEND DEVELOPER INTERN @INVIDEO

3rd June - 19th July 2019 // Mumbai, MH // @Experience Letter

- ▷ Creating new user facing modules for MVP product based on Angular 7.
- ▷ Converting designs from InVision into pixel-perfect responsive screens.
- ▶ Helped in fixing cross-browser inconsistencies in the interface.

PROJECTS

mongodb-aggregation-builder

NPM: mongodb-aggregation-builder
MongoDB Aggregation Pipeline constructor.

Easy Event Webapp

<u>Repo: easyevent-graphql</u>

Event booking app using React & GraphQL

Flashify

https://github.com/smithg09/Flashify Flashcard Mobile App using React Native

Tekie-content-editor NPM Library

npmjs.com/package/tekie-content-editor Web based WYSIWYG editor library for React.

Covid19 Tracker

https://covid19.smithgajjar.dev/ ProgressiveWebApp for tracking COVID19

GraphQL Nodejs Backend starter

Repo: <u>nx-node-apollo-grahql-mongo</u>
Built using Typescript/MongoDB/GraphQL.

OTHER PROJECTS

- ⊳ Serverless AWS Node API @github.com/smithg09/serverless-node-api
- ► Tekie-blockly NPM Library @npmjs.com/package/tekie-blockly
- ▶ A REST API developed using Deno @github.com/smithg09/Deno_REST_API
- ${\scriptstyle \triangleright} \ \text{React Redux Laravel Blog Application} \ @ \underline{|| \text{daravel-react-mysql-blog-starter}|}$